235 Jaycee Court • Mankato, MN United States, 56001 • (507)-351-6589 • budhathoki.suhan@gmail.com

Professional Summary

Experienced Web Developer committed to mantaining cutting edge technical skills and up-to-date industry knowledge. Graphic Design Specialist with practical knowlegde of design techniques, tools and principles for production of technical plans. Accomplished Graphic Design specialist with 6 years experience creating themes and graphics for specialized content management systems

Work Experience

07/2010 - 08/2013 Surya Multipurpose Co-operative Society, Kathmandu, Bagmati Nepal *IT Consultant*

- Update knowledge and skills to keep up with rapid advancements in computer technology.
- Provide technical support to designers, marketing and sales departments, suppliers, engineers and other team members throughout the product development and implementation process.
- Specify power supply requirements and configuration, drawing on system performance expectations and design specifications.
- Provide training and support to system designers and users.

09/2011 - 12/2015 Upwork Global Inc., www.upwork.com United States *Freelance Web Developer*

- Create designs, concepts, and sample layouts based on knowledge of layout principles and esthetic design concepts.
- Confer with clients to discuss and determine layout design.
- Develop graphics and layouts for product illustrations, company logos, and Internet websites.

Create web models or prototypes that include physical, interface, logical, or data models.

- Create searchable indices for web page content.
- Develop and document style guidelines for web site content.
- Online Profile at http://www.upwork.com/o/profiles/users/_~011def19fe81991762/

Education

2011 - 2013 National School of Open schooling High School Diploma in Computer Science GPA: 2.6

Skills

- Programming
- · English Language
- Critical Thinking
- Computers and Electronics
- Speaking
- Design
- Complex Problem Solving
- Desire to learn and gain experience
- Time Management